# Why Zano for Patients  When you travel for healthcare, you deserve privacy.
Traditional payment methods leave a trail.
Credit cards.
Bank transfers.
Wire services.
Every one of them knows where your money went and why.
Insurance companies can see your medical history through payments.
Banks can freeze accounts if they don't like your choices.
Governments can track every dollar you spend on healthcare.
Is that really the world you want to live in?  Zano is different.
It's a privacy-focused cryptocurrency.
When you pay with Zano, only you and your provider know.
No banks.
No insurance companies.
No government surveillance.
Just private payment for private healthcare.
Download the Zano wallet.
It takes five minutes.
Get some Zano from an exchange or a friend.
Pay your provider directly.
Instantly.
Privately.
It's that simple.
Oasara connects you with verified providers who accept Zano.
Quality healthcare.
Privacy-respecting payment.
Global access.
Your body.
Your health.
Your money.
Your choice.
In the following tutorials, we'll show you exactly how to set up your Zano wallet and make your first private payment.
Welcome to healthcare freedom.