# Create Your Zano Wallet  Open the Zano wallet.
The first time you open it, you'll see this welcome screen.
This is where you'll create YOUR wallet - a wallet that belongs only to you.
Press your finger on the button that says Create New Wallet.
This will generate a brand new wallet just for you.
Give your wallet a name.
This is just for you to recognize it.
Type something simple like My Zano Wallet or your first name.
Now create a password.
This password protects YOUR wallet on YOUR computer.
Choose something you can remember but others cannot guess.
Write it down and keep it somewhere safe - NOT on your computer.
Type your password again to confirm it.
Take your time - accuracy matters more than speed.
STOP.
This is the most important screen you will ever see.
These words are your RECOVERY SEED.
They ARE your wallet.
Anyone who has these words can access your money.
Write them down on PAPER.
Not on your computer.
PAPER.
Store that paper somewhere safe - a lockbox, a safe, somewhere secure.
Write down every word in order.
One through twenty-four.
Double-check each word.
A single wrong letter could lock you out forever.
These words are more valuable than gold.
Treat them that way.
The wallet will now ask you to verify some words.
This confirms you wrote them down correctly.
Look at your paper and type the words it asks for.
Congratulations.
You have created YOUR wallet.
This wallet belongs to you and only you.
No bank can freeze it.
No government can seize it.
You are now in control of your own financial destiny.
This is your wallet dashboard.
From here you can receive payments, send payments, and check your balance.
In the next tutorial, we'll show you how to receive your first Zano.
You have taken a powerful step today.
You created a wallet that YOU control.
Remember: keep your recovery words SAFE.
They are your financial freedom.